<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opensource firmware on DIY zigbee devices</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/tags/opensource-firmware/</link><description>Recent content in Opensource firmware on DIY zigbee devices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diyruz.github.io/tags/opensource-firmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CO2 (carbon dioxide) Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</guid><description>Github Carbon dioxide has a very negative effect on the human body and is a carcinogen. Being in a room with a high concentration of CO2 can cause weakness, drowsiness, headaches, and problems concentrating. In this regard, it is necessary to monitor the level of CO2 and take measures to reduce it.
Today there are several options available for CO2 measurement, the most interesting being the SenseAir S8. His readings will be displayed on the Zigbee network.</description></item><item><title>Flower sensor Zigbee</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/flower/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/flower/</guid><description>Github Version 1 A lot of time has passed since the appearance of Mi Flora, but Jager never dared to purchase it. First of all, the fact that it was bluetooth stopped, and this automatically created problems on a scale at home and the second reason was the cost, taking into account the fact that Jager needed 20-30 pieces. Decision, do it himself. Taking into account the development of his home Zigbee network, the proven E18-MS1-PCB module was taken as a basis.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v1</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</guid><description>Github
This is a kind of universal remote control, which displays the most frequently used functions in a particular room. This can be lighting control, multimedia equipment, various UD scenarios, etc.
This remote control will live in the kitchen, the icons show that it will be possible to control the light, hood, music, set the timer.
The device is based on a module from EBYTE E18-MS1-PCB or E18-MS1PA1-PCB if an increased communication range is required.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v2</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</guid><description>Github
The first version of the Zigbee remote control is good, but this option is not suitable when mobility is needed. For this reason, a second version appeared, in which Jager tried to make a more compact version.
Since 20 buttons are not always and not always needed, Jager had to come up with a board design that allows you to assemble 3 versions of remotes, for 20, 12, and 8 buttons.</description></item><item><title>Geiger counter Zigbee</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/geiger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/geiger/</guid><description>Github
We all know what radiation is and its harmful effects on humans. Since this danger is not tangible, in connection with this the idea was born to make an indicator for continuous monitoring of the radiation situation.
The device is not designed to measure the level of radiation in the epicenter of a nuclear explosion, but it allows you to constantly monitor changes in background values. This can be useful in the event of man-made disasters or when you yourself or others bring something with an increased background radiation into the house.</description></item><item><title>LeTV Zigbee remote</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</guid><description>Github
Some time ago, digging TaoBao, Jager has found an interesting miniature ZigBee remote control keypad with eight buttons. As this device is powered by a CC2530 chip, an idea appeared in Jager&amp;rsquo;s head to flash it with a great freepad firmware, which was used in Jager&amp;rsquo;s previous remote controls.
UPD: This keypad has appeared on AliExpress
Keypad has 8 buttons, two-colored led, and is powered by CR2032 lithium cell.</description></item><item><title>Reed Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/reed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/reed/</guid><description>Github
Continuing the automation of the apartment, the idea came to make a doorbell button with ZigBee support. Sergey decided to use the factory model CACAZI A8 as a case with an acceptable cost - about 230 rubles at the time of original writing.
The heart of the device is the popular E18-MS1-IPX module. You can also use the version with a built-in antenna, but Sergey thought that the signal quality behind the metal entrance door would not be very good.</description></item></channel></rss>