<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opensource firmware on DIY zigbee devices</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/tags/opensource-firmware/</link><description>Recent content in Opensource firmware on DIY zigbee devices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diyruz.github.io/tags/opensource-firmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CO2 (carbon dioxide) Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</guid><description>Github Air quality sensor Original by Jager
Carbon dioxide has a very negative effect on the human body and is a carcinogen. Being in a room with a high concentration of CO2 can cause weakness, drowsiness, headaches, and problems concentrating. In this regard, it is necessary to monitor the level of CO2 and take measures to reduce it.
Today there are several options available for CO2 measurement, the most interesting being the SenseAir S8.</description></item><item><title>Flower sensor Zigbee</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/flower/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/flower/</guid><description>Github Version 1 A lot of time has passed since the appearance of Mi Flora, but Jager never dared to purchase it. First of all, the fact that it was bluetooth stopped, and this automatically created problems on a scale at home and the second reason was the cost, taking into account the fact that Jager needed 20-30 pieces. Decision, do it himself. Taking into account the development of his home Zigbee network, the proven E18-MS1-PCB module was taken as a basis.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v1</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</guid><description>Github
This is a kind of universal remote control, which displays the most frequently used functions in a particular room. This can be lighting control, multimedia equipment, various UD scenarios, etc.
This remote control will live in the kitchen, the icons show that it will be possible to control the light, hood, music, set the timer.
The device is based on a module from EBYTE E18-MS1-PCB or E18-MS1PA1-PCB if an increased communication range is required.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v2</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</guid><description>Github
The first version of the Zigbee remote control is good, but this option is not suitable when mobility is needed. For this reason, a second version appeared, in which Jager tried to make a more compact version.
Since 20 buttons are not always and not always needed, Jager had to come up with a board design that allows you to assemble 3 versions of remotes, for 20, 12, and 8 buttons.</description></item><item><title>Geiger counter Zigbee</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/geiger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/geiger/</guid><description>Github
Geiger counter How to join Reset to FN rebooting device 5 times with interval less than 10 seconds, led will start flashing during reset How to change parameters Sensitivity:
mosquitto_pub -t &amp;quot;zigbee2mqtt/FN/BUTTON_NUM/set/sensitivity&amp;quot; -m '100'
This attribute will be used on reporting, pulsesCount * sensitivity. You can use this attribute to setup reporting in your prefered units radiationDosePerHour = pulsesCount * sensitivity
Led feedback (ON/OFF) (default=ON)
mosquitto_pub -t &amp;quot;zigbee2mqtt/FN/1/set/led_feedback&amp;quot; -m 'ON'</description></item><item><title>LeTV Zigbee remote</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</guid><description>Github
Some time ago, digging TaoBao, Jager has found an interesting miniature ZigBee remote control keypad with eight buttons. As this device is powered by a CC2530 chip, an idea appeared in Jager&amp;rsquo;s head to flash it with a great freepad firmware, which was used in Jager&amp;rsquo;s previous remote controls.
UPD: This keypad has appeared on AliExpress
Keypad has 8 buttons, two-colored led, and is powered by CR2032 lithium cell.</description></item><item><title>Reed Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/reed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/reed/</guid><description>Github
How to join: If device in FN(factory new) state: Press and hold button (1) for 2-3 seconds, until device start flashing led Wait, in case of successfull join, device will flash led 5 times If join failed, device will flash led 3 times If device in a network: Hold button (1) for 10 seconds, this will reset device to FN(factory new) status Go to step 1 for FN device How to add device into zigbe2mqtt Use external converters feature</description></item></channel></rss>