<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FreePad on DIY zigbee devices</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/tags/freepad/</link><description>Recent content in FreePad on DIY zigbee devices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diyruz.github.io/tags/freepad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v1</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</guid><description>Github
This is a kind of universal remote control, which displays the most frequently used functions in a particular room. This can be lighting control, multimedia equipment, various UD scenarios, etc.
This remote control will live in the kitchen, the icons show that it will be possible to control the light, hood, music, set the timer.
The device is based on a module from EBYTE E18-MS1-PCB or E18-MS1PA1-PCB if an increased communication range is required.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v2</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</guid><description>Github
The first version of the Zigbee remote control is good, but this option is not suitable when mobility is needed. For this reason, a second version appeared, in which Jager tried to make a more compact version.
Since 20 buttons are not always and not always needed, Jager had to come up with a board design that allows you to assemble 3 versions of remotes, for 20, 12, and 8 buttons.</description></item><item><title>LeTV Zigbee remote</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</guid><description>Github
Some time ago, digging TaoBao, Jager has found an interesting miniature ZigBee remote control keypad with eight buttons. As this device is powered by a CC2530 chip, an idea appeared in Jager&amp;rsquo;s head to flash it with a great freepad firmware, which was used in Jager&amp;rsquo;s previous remote controls.
UPD: This keypad has appeared on AliExpress
Keypad has 8 buttons, two-colored led, and is powered by CR2032 lithium cell.</description></item></channel></rss>