<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gerber only on DIY zigbee devices</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/tags/gerber-only/</link><description>Recent content in Gerber only on DIY zigbee devices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diyruz.github.io/tags/gerber-only/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zintercom</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/zintercom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/zintercom/</guid><description>Github Zintercom Zigbee Intercom Automator This device is designed to control the matrix intercom using Zigbee.
Using zigbee2mqtt you can:
Receive notification when the intercom rings. (also support direct bind) Mute the sound on the intercom handset. Automatically or manually open the door or hang up when the intercom rings. There are 4 work modes:
Never - ordinary work mode, use handset to control Once - one time open door when intercom rings Always - open door when intercom rings Drop - hangs up all intercom rings, right after start You can change the operating mode with z2m or by pressing the button.</description></item><item><title>CO2 (carbon dioxide) Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</guid><description>Github Carbon dioxide has a very negative effect on the human body and is a carcinogen. Being in a room with a high concentration of CO2 can cause weakness, drowsiness, headaches, and problems concentrating. In this regard, it is necessary to monitor the level of CO2 and take measures to reduce it.
Today there are several options available for CO2 measurement, the most interesting being the SenseAir S8. His readings will be displayed on the Zigbee network.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v1</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v1/</guid><description>Github
This is a kind of universal remote control, which displays the most frequently used functions in a particular room. This can be lighting control, multimedia equipment, various UD scenarios, etc.
This remote control will live in the kitchen, the icons show that it will be possible to control the light, hood, music, set the timer.
The device is based on a module from EBYTE E18-MS1-PCB or E18-MS1PA1-PCB if an increased communication range is required.</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote v2</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad_v2/</guid><description>Github
The first version of the Zigbee remote control is good, but this option is not suitable when mobility is needed. For this reason, a second version appeared, in which Jager tried to make a more compact version.
Since 20 buttons are not always and not always needed, Jager had to come up with a board design that allows you to assemble 3 versions of remotes, for 20, 12, and 8 buttons.</description></item></channel></rss>