<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on DIY zigbee devices</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on DIY zigbee devices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diyruz.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CO2 (carbon dioxide) Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/airsense/</guid><description>Air quality sensor Original by Jager
Carbon dioxide has a very negative effect on the human body and is a carcinogen. Being in a room with a high concentration of CO2 can cause weakness, drowsiness, headaches, and problems concentrating. In this regard, it is necessary to monitor the level of CO2 and take measures to reduce it.
Today there are several options available for CO2 measurement, the most interesting being the SenseAir S8.</description></item><item><title>Flower sensor Zigbee</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/flower/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/flower/</guid><description>How to join: If device in FN(factory new) state: Press and hold button (1) for 2-3 seconds, until device start flashing led Wait, in case of successfull join, device will flash led 5 times If join failed, device will flash led 3 times If device in a network: Hold button (1) for 10 seconds, this will reset device to FN(factory new) status Go to step 1 for FN device Troubleshooting If a device does not connect to your coordinator, please try the following:</description></item><item><title>FreePad Zigbee remote</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/freepad/</guid><description>Freepad Freepad is an open source Zigbee remote intended to be used to have a customizable keypad to control your smart home devices.
Read more here: https://modkam.ru/?p=1264
Features list: Single/double/tripple/quadriple/many_x/hold&amp;amp;release Touchlink reset ONOFF bind Level control bind Bindings configuration Remote reset How to join: Press and hold first button for 3-10 seconds(depends whter or not device is on a network), until device start flashing led Wait, in case of successfull join, device will flash led 5 times If join failed, device will flash led 3 times How to use touch link Deprecated due to memory issues, you can use FREEPAD_ENABLE_TL macros if you want to compile with TL functionality</description></item><item><title>Geiger counter Zigbee</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/geiger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/geiger/</guid><description>Geiger counter How to join Reset to FN rebooting device 5 times with interval less than 10 seconds, led will start flashing during reset How to change parameters Sensitivity:
mosquitto_pub -t &amp;quot;zigbee2mqtt/FN/BUTTON_NUM/set/sensitivity&amp;quot; -m '100'
This attribute will be used on reporting, pulsesCount * sensitivity. You can use this attribute to setup reporting in your prefered units radiationDosePerHour = pulsesCount * sensitivity
Led feedback (ON/OFF) (default=ON)
mosquitto_pub -t &amp;quot;zigbee2mqtt/FN/1/set/led_feedback&amp;quot; -m 'ON'</description></item><item><title>LeTV Zigbee remote</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/letv/</guid><description>Some time ago, digging TaoBao, I&amp;rsquo;ve found an interesting miniature ZigBee remote control keypad with eight buttons. As this device is powered by a CC2530 chip, an idea appeared in my head to flash it with a great freepad firmware, which was used in my previous remote controls.
UPD: This keypad has appeared on Aliexpress
Keypad has 8 buttons, two-colored led, and is powered by CR2032 lithium cell.
It is quite easy to disassemble this device.</description></item><item><title>Reed Zigbee sensor</title><link>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/reed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://diyruz.github.io/posts/reed/</guid><description>How to join: If device in FN(factory new) state: Press and hold button (1) for 2-3 seconds, until device start flashing led Wait, in case of successfull join, device will flash led 5 times If join failed, device will flash led 3 times If device in a network: Hold button (1) for 10 seconds, this will reset device to FN(factory new) status Go to step 1 for FN device How to add device into zigbe2mqtt Use external converters feature</description></item></channel></rss>